It’s hard to understand how people could not feel it.
É difícil entender como as pessoas não conseguiram sentir isso.
They all have suffered so much.
Todos Eles sofreram tanto.
Whatever it is, for the Divine they do not suffer
Seja o que for, pelo Divino, Eles não sofrem.
and they come on this earth to show how stupid we are,
E Eles vêm a esta Terra para mostrar o quanto nós somos estúpidos,
how we have not been able,
o quanto não temos sido capazes…
to see the Truth, to see the reality.
de ver a Verdade, de ver a realidade.
But we repeat the mistakes again and again,
Mas nós repetimos os erros repetidamente,
because we do not know ourselves,
porque não conhecemos a nós mesmos,
which is the only instrument by which you can know the Divine.
que é o único instrumento pelo qual você pode conhecer o Divino.
And when we do not know ourselves we cannot understand the Divine.
E quando não conhecemos a nós mesmos, não podemos entender o Divino.
Still, it’s such a great thing to see so many of you are
Ainda assim, é algo tão grandioso ver que tantos de vocês…
there in that subtle area of the Spirit.
estão aí nessa área sutil do Espírito.
That you have the sensitivity, that you can feel,
Que vocês têm a sensibilidade, que podem sentir…
the beauty of their lives, the greatness, the purity,
a beleza das vidas Deles, a grandeza, a pureza,
the innocence of these great incarnations who came on this earth.
a inocência dessas grandes encarnações que vieram a esta Terra.
But with all that, we have a very great responsibility also.
Mas com tudo isso, nós temos uma responsabilidade muito grande também.
Christ had only 12 disciples who didn’t even get their Realization till Christ lived.
Cristo teve apenas 12 discípulos...
Afterwards they got Realization – 12 of them.
Depois eles obtiveram a Realização, 12 deles.
And imagine, somebody like Thomas came to India.
E imaginem, alguém como Tomé veio para a Índia.
So, how they took so much responsibility. They were just ordinary fishermen.
Assim, o modo como eles assumiram tanta responsabilidade.
They didn’t care for anything else, but they thought, “This is the Truth
Eles não se importavam com mais nada, mas pensavam: "Esta é a Verdade…"
and that we have to spread this, this is our responsibility.”
"e nós temos de espalhar isso, esta é a nossa responsabilidade."
We are so many.
Nós somos tantos.
That is our responsibility. Is not only to enjoy yourself,
Essa é a nossa responsabilidade. Não é apenas regozijar-se,
but to spread Sahaja Yoga
mas expandir a Sahaja Yoga e praticá-la.
Moreover, to have an ideal life,
Além disso, ter uma vida ideal,
that people could see us: how we behave, how we talk,
para que as pessoas possam nos ver: como nos comportamos, como falamos,
how we treat each other, how we love each other,
como tratamos uns aos outros, como amamos uns aos outros,
how we understand each other, how we run to help each other –
como entendemos uns aos outros, como corremos para ajudar uns aos outros,
like one body.
como um só corpo.
The message of Christ’s life is love.
A mensagem da vida de Cristo é o amor.
He openly talked about it.
Ele falou abertamente sobre isso.
Before that, I don’t think any incarnation talked like that, in that manner,
Antes disso, não creio que nenhuma encarnação tenha falado assim,
He told His disciples that, “The greatest joy for Me is to see that you love each other.”
Ele disse aos Seus discípulos: "A maior alegria para Mim..."
All those things that have really made our society,
Todas essas coisas que realmente fizeram nossa sociedade,
made our lives miserable of jealousies and pettiness,
tornaram nossas vidas infelizes de inveja e mesquinharias,
small-mindedness has to go. Otherwise you are not Sahaja Yogis.
a mesquinhez tem de ir embora. Caso contrário, vocês não são Sahaja Yogis.
Where is the time for jealousy?
Onde há tempo para a inveja?
There is no mind, this…
Não há nenhuma mente, isto…
that can see those things, anymore.
que possa ver essas coisas, nunca mais.
So, all of us have to evolve,
Então, todos nós temos de evoluir…
and the sign of evolution is not how much we can talk about Sahaja Yoga,
e o sinal da evolução não é o quanto podemos falar sobre a Sahaja Yoga,
how much we can practice Sahaja Yoga,
o quanto podemos praticar a Sahaja Yoga,
how much we spread Sahaja Yoga.
o quanto nós expandimos a Sahaja Yoga.
That’s not the sign, don’t be convinced by that.
Esse não é o sinal, não sejam convencidos por isso.
But the sign of Sahaja Yoga is that
Mas o sinal da Sahaja Yoga é o quanto podemos amar uns aos outros,
how much we understand each other,
o quanto entendemos uns aos outros,
how much we can endure for others with great joy
o quanto podemos suportar pelos outros com grande alegria…
and how much we do not bother about ourselves,
e o quanto não nos preocupamos com nós mesmos,
our families, our children.
com nossas famílias, com nossos filhos.
This ‘mine, my, me’ has too.
Este "meu, minha, eu" tem de ir embora.
It doesn’t go by saying “go”. It’s a state, again.
Isso não vai embora dizendo "vá". É um estado, novamente.
But then only you should be convinced,
Mas somente então você deve estar convencido: "Agora eu sou um Sahaja Yogi."
Christ has said, “Love thy neighbor as thyself!”
Cristo disse: "Amai o próximo como a ti mesmo."
I would say that
Eu diria:
you have to love every Sahaja Yogi as yourself,
você tem de amar cada Sahaja Yogi como a si mesmo,
because they are part and parcel of this body.
porque eles são parte integrante deste corpo.
You cannot afford to hate someone.
Você não pode se permitir odiar alguém.
Of course, those who are useless are thrown out of the body.
É claro, aqueles que são inúteis são expulsos do corpo,
But those who are there living, you must love them.
mas aqueles que estão lá vivendo, vocês devem amá-los.
I think this is the message of Christ
Eu acho que esta é a mensagem de Cristo…
and other message is absolute morality,
e a outra mensagem é a moralidade absoluta,
absolute morality.
moralidade absoluta.
As He has said that, “Thou shalt not have adulterous eyes”
Como Ele disse: "Não terás olhos adúlteros",
is such a subtle thing to say,
é uma coisa tão sutil de se dizer,
that you should not have eyes which have adultery in them.
que você não deve ter olhos que tenham adultério neles.
It doesn’t mean only for women but it also mean for saints.
Não significa apenas em relação a mulheres, mas também em relação às coisas.
It also means for properties, it also means for the success of others.
Significa também em relação a propriedades,
Adultery means the one where you try to aggress
Adultério significa aquilo onde você tenta agredir…
and to be greedy about it.
e ser ganancioso a respeito.
If there is greed or if there is lust in your eyes,
Se houver ganância ou se houver luxúria em seus olhos,
then it’s an adulterous eyes.
então são olhos adúlteros.
It is very subtle, I know.
É muito sutil, Eu sei.
It is very subtle
É muito sutil, e a atenção é a melhor forma…
which communicates to you
que lhe comunica…
whether you are above lust and greed or not.
se você está acima da luxúria e da ganância ou não.
But the more you try to rise above these things,
Mas quanto mais você tenta se elevar acima dessas coisas,
your heart opens
seu coração se abre e você começa a desfrutar suas virtudes, sua moralidade.
You enjoy, you don’t think you are moral, you don’t think that way,
Você desfruta, você não pensa que você é moral, você não pensa dessa forma,
but you enjoy that state where you are really moral because you are moral.
mas você desfruta esse estado onde você é realmente moral porque você é moral.
You just enjoy yourself.
Você apenas se regozija.
It’s a headache to be interested in some woman, interested in some man. It’s a headache.
É uma dor de cabeça estar interessado em alguma mulher,
And once you are detached,
E uma vez que você esteja desapegado,
the joy is complete…
a alegria é completa,
…because you are one with reality, pure reality.
porque você é um só com a realidade, a realidade pura.
There is no …
Não há inibições, nem restrições, nem tabus, nada,
but just you are that!
mas simplesmente você é isso. Ninguém tem de lhe dizer.
If you are gold, you are gold.
Se você é ouro, você é ouro.
Nobody has to tell you, “Now, you don’t behave like non-gold”,
Ninguém tem de lhe dizer: "Agora, não se comporte como não-ouro",
you are gold, so you are gold.
você é ouro, então você é ouro.
That’s the power!
Esse é o poder.
And the power of a Sahaja Yogi is that he is the purest form of human being.
E o poder de um Sahaja Yogi é que ele é a forma mais pura do ser humano.
Without the power what are we? Nothing.
Sem o poder, o que nós somos? Nada.
The purest form
A forma mais pura,
and in the purest form of love
e na forma mais pura de amor,
you get the purest form of knowledge.
você obtém a forma mais pura de conhecimento.
This is [kaivaldya?] is the,
Isto é kaivalya, é o conhecimento absoluto…
and absolute love,
e amor absoluto,
detached, pure.
desapegado, puro.
That time when you are in that state,
Nesse momento em que você está nesse estado,
you just watch anything, see anything,
você apenas observa qualquer coisa, vê qualquer coisa,
all the power of giving joy from everything
todo o poder de dar alegria a partir de tudo…
just starts bubbling into you and you don’t see the bad things at all, you never see the bad things.
simplesmente começa a borbulhar dentro de você...
The power of enjoying everything
O poder de desfrutar tudo…
is the power of Sahaja Yogis, to enjoy everything.
é o poder dos Sahaja Yogis, desfrutar tudo.
Anything can be enjoyed,
Qualquer coisa pode ser desfrutada,
any small thing can be enjoyed,
qualquer pequena coisa pode ser desfrutada,
any big thing can be enjoyed.
qualquer coisa grande pode ser desfrutada.
But impurities one cannot enjoy,
Mas as impurezas não se pode desfrutar; a imoralidade, você não pode desfrutar.
It’s not enjoyment, it’s just a fascination maybe, I don’t know what it is called as,
Não é prazer, é apenas um fascínio talvez, não sei do que isso é chamado,
as I cannot enjoy then I don’t know what it is.
como Eu não posso desfrutar, então não sei o que é.
But what you enjoy really is the purity of another personality,
Mas o que você desfruta realmente é a pureza da outra pessoa,
the purity of this,
a pureza disto,
all that is done by someone with such pure heart.
tudo que é feito por alguém com um coração tão puro.
And the deeper you seek,
E quanto mais profundamente você vê, isso se torna cada vez mais simples.
Then you don’t say smart things, no, you don’t,
Então você não diz coisas espertas, não, você não diz, não tem de se exibir, nada.
You just say simple, sweet nice things.
Você apenas diz coisas simples, doces e boas.
It’s so touching, so beautiful,
É tão tocante, tão belo,
but must allow the deeper love within us to come out.
mas devemos permitir que o amor mais profundo dentro de nós saia.
Many people love also but they don’t know how to express it.
Muitas pessoas amam também, mas elas não sabem como expressar isso.
There are many people who are misunderstood, because they don’t know how to express their love.
Há muitas pessoas que são mal compreendidas,
In Sahaja Yoga you have to learn the yukti,
Na Sahaja Yoga, você tem de aprender a yukti, a técnica.
“Yukti” is a very sweet word, not technique is not,
"Yukti" é uma palavra muito doce, técnica não é,
technique deals with something very materialistic.
técnica lida com algo muito materialista.
But yukti means the trick, trick of the trade,
Mas yukti significa o truque, o segredo do ofício,
what to say when that would really just pierce,
o que dizer quando isso realmente apenas perfure,
like a dart in the heart of someone, the beautiful feeling.
como um dardo no coração de alguém, o belo sentimento.
That one has to understand and practice.
Isso tem de ser compreendido e praticado.
All little-little things here and there,
Todas as pequenas coisas aqui e ali,
little turning here and there is an art of living a Sahaja Yoga life.
pequenas curvas aqui e ali são a arte de viver uma vida Sahaja Yoga.
And I’ve seen children say such sweet-sweet things.
E Eu tenho visto crianças dizerem coisas tão doces.
That’s why Christ has said that, “You have to be like children
É por isso que Cristo disse: "Vocês têm de ser como crianças…"
to enter into the Kingdom of God”, but I would say, “to stay in the Kingdom of God.”
"para entrar no Reino de Deus", mas Eu diria: "Para permanecer no Reino de Deus,"
You have to be simple like children, deep and simple.
"Vocês têm de ser simples como crianças, profundos e simples."
is a Divine congregation of all the Gods and Goddesses,
é uma congregação Divina de todos os Deuses e Deusas,
is very symbolic to Me,
é muito simbólico para Mim,
because this represents the whole world,
porque representa o mundo inteiro,
it represents the problems of the whole world
representa os problemas do mundo inteiro e também as soluções.
It’s such a beautiful idea.
É uma ideia tão bela.
I don’t know how it worked into My head that I started this kind of a,
Eu não sei como isso funcionou em Minha cabeça, que comecei este tipo de…
beautiful congregation to meet you all.
bela congregação para encontrar todos vocês.
It was very nice yesterday, you kept awake all the while and came to see Me.
Foi muito bom ontem, todos vocês ficaram acordados o tempo todo e vieram Me ver.
I could meet all of you and I could have some rapport.
Eu pude encontrar todos vocês e pude ter alguma afinidade.
I couldn’t say much, I was just smiling at you,
Eu não pude dizer muito, Eu fiquei apenas sorrindo para vocês,
but just I could express My love and you gave Me that chance.
mas Eu simplesmente pude expressar Meu amor e vocês Me deram essa chance.
I must thank you very much for that.
Eu devo agradecer-lhes muito por isso.